northlight-images.co.uk 2014-02-10

# Northlight images Cookies and Privacy Policy

## For web site visitors, on-line print sales and the Northlight Images Newsletter

This privacy policy sets out how Northlight Images uses and protects any information that you give Northlight Images when you use this website.

Northlight Images is a trading name of Northlight IT Ltd., a company registered in England and Wales, No. 3589027.  
Our UK VAT registration number is 715 6562 29

### Contact details :

Northlight Images, 86 Harrow Road Leicester, Leicestershire, UK. LE3 0JW (Maps) Telephone (Mon-Fri. 9am-5pm) +44 (0)116 291 9092    

More details **About our Business**

We have a separate set of **terms and conditions** relating to all our commercial photography, training and consultancy services.

Northlight Images is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

Northlight Images may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes.

This policy last updated and is effective from July 5, 2013.

#### What we collect

We may collect the following information:

  * Name
  * Contact information including email address
  * Demographic information such as post code, preferences and interests
  * Other information relevant to customer surveys and/or offers

#### What we do with the information we gather

We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:

  * Internal record keeping.
  * We may use the information to improve our products and services.
  * We may periodically send promotional email about new products, special offers or other information which we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided.
  * From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research purposes. We may contact you by email, phone, fax or mail.
  * We may use the information to customise the website according to your interests.

For surveys and newsletters we will only contact people who have indicated that they are happy to receive information from us.

#### Security

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect on-line.

## How we use cookies

A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the web site.

#### Advertising content and third party cookies

Advertising helps us defray the running costs of the Northlight Images web site - the content of some adverts is dependent on where you are viewing the site from. All advertising from third parties is offered for your information, without any recommendation or endorsement from Northlight Images.

**Please be aware that some of the advertisers on our site may use cookies and or web tracking technologies in connection with advertisements placed on our site through our participation in the Google AdSense program.**

In particular, Google uses cookies such as the [DART](http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/faq.aspx) cookie to enable it to serve ads to users based on their visit to this site and other sites on the Internet.

Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network [privacy policy](http://www.google.co.uk/privacy_ads.html). There is more information about this available from [Google.](http://www.google.com/intl/en-GB/privacy.html "Google UK privacy policy")

**You can usually alter your browser's behaviour with regard to cookies, such as accepting cookies from sites visited, but declining 3rd party (advertiser's) cookies.**

This site is a participant in the Amazon Europe S.à r.l. Associates Programme, an affiliate advertising programme designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to Amazon .co.uk , .fr and .de sites.

#### Links to other web sites

Our web site may contain links to enable you to visit other web sites of interest easily. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

#### Controlling your personal information

Only if you subscribe to the Northlight Images Mailing List, or if you are a registered customer of Northlight Images will we make use of any personal information you have provided us with. You can unsubscribe from our mailing lists by selecting the unsubscribe link on any Mailing List emails we send to you, or you can contact us at any time requesting to be removed from our Mailing List.

We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we are compelled to do so by law.

You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the UK Data Protection Act 1998. A £10.00 fee will be payable. If you would like a copy of the information held on you please write to Customer Services, Northlight Images, 86 Harrow Rd., Leicester, LE3 0JW.

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to or email us as soon as possible, at address below. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.

### Contact details :

Northlight Images, 86 Harrow Road Leicester, Leicestershire, UK. LE3 0JW (Maps) Telephone (Mon-Fri. 9am-5pm) +44 (0)116 291 9092    

* * *

**You can search all the hundreds of articles on the site for more information**

**_Have you found an article on the site useful or helpful?_** If so, please consider sharing a link to the article or mentioning it on a forum - Thanks to everyone who's helped the site become better known. _**Explore our site...** _Digital Black and White photography and printing \- some of Keiths thoughts, techniques and tips for those interested in a digital approach to black and white. New site content appears on the News, articles and reviews page. We've lots of original Photography Articles and Photography Reviews on the site to help anyone interested in photography. 

__**Thanks to the visitors** who've made Amazon purchases (any kinds of items whatosever)  
via: [Amazon UK](http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&location=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.co.uk%2FPhotography-Accessories-Bundles-Scopes%2Fb%3Fie%3DUTF8%26node%3D560834%26ref%255F%3Dsa%255Fmenu%255Fp2&tag=northlightima-21&linkCode=ur2&camp=1634&creative=19450)/[Amazon France](http://www.amazon.fr/b?%5Fencoding=UTF8&site-redirect=&node=13921051&tag=northimage01-21&linkCode=ur2&camp=1642&creative=6746)/[Amazon Germany](http://www.amazon.de/b?%5Fencoding=UTF8&site-redirect=de&node=562066&tag=northimage05-21&linkCode=ur2&camp=1638&creative=6742)/[Amazon USA](http://www.amazon.com/b?%5Fencoding=UTF8&site-redirect=&node=13900861&tag=northligimage-20&linkCode=ur2&camp=1789&creative=9325)/[Amazon Canada  
](http://www.amazon.ca/b?%5Fencoding=UTF8&site-redirect=&node=677230011&tag=northimage-20&linkCode=ur2&camp=15121&creative=330641)It won't save extra money we're afraid, but it does help in the running of the site, and we really appreciate it...__

Northlight Images is based in Leicester in the UK and supplies Commercial Photography services  
Visiting Leicester or wondering where it is? We have views from the Leicester traffic cameras.
